Rekik H Biyadgilign

Dallas, TX 75243

945-257-9966 • <u>rekik.biyadgilign@gmail.com</u> • <u>Rekik Biyadgilign | LinkedIn</u> • <u>rekik</u> Work Authorization: US-Citizen

FULL STACK JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

Passionate, Self-motivated, and Experienced Full Stack web developer with 4+ years of experience in enterprise-level web development using **Angular, React, React-Native** and **NodeJS** through all phases of Software Development Life Cycle. Experience on trending technologies and tools of JavaScript, NodeJS, Core Java, J2EE, Design pattern, HTML5, Angular, React, React-Native, CSS, Bootstrap, MongoDB, MySQL, Web Services, Git and more. Strong system design, coding, and troubleshooting skills. An effective team member who communicates closely with the team and is always eager to learn about new technologies.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Software Development Life Cycle • Full-Stack Development • UI/UX Design • Application Deployment / Maintenance • Code Review & Optimization • Testing & Documentation • Web Services • Object-Oriented Programming • Agile Methodologies

- Languages: JavaScript ES6, Nodejs, Typescript, core java
- ▶ Web: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JSON, SPA, ¡Query, EJS, AJAX, Redux
- Frameworks: Angular, Expess.js, Mongoose, React
- ➤ Libraries: React, React-Native
- > Test / Debugger Tools: Jasmine, Karma, Jest, developer Tools, Mocha, Chai
- ➤ Web Services: RESTful, JSON, REST
- > Databases: MongoDB, MySQL
- > Tools: Visual Studio Code, Collaborative Git, Swagger, Postman
- **Platforms:** Window, Linux, Cloud Deployment
- ➤ Cloud Computing: AWS-S3, EC2, G-cloud, App engine, Compute engine
- **Design Patterns**: MVC, RxJS observables, Singleton, Observer, Façade, Decorator
- > SDLC: Agile, Scrum, Waterfall
- **DevOps:** Jenkins

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MIUCOMPRO (Aug 2021 - Nov 2022)

Position: Front-end Developer

Responsibilities:

- Used React-Router to turn application into Single Page Application
- Developed user interface by using the **React JS** for **SPA** development.
- Worked using React JS components, Forms, Events, Keys, Router
- Interacted with java controllers (jQuery, AJAX, and JSON to write/read data from back-end systems).
- Develop in SPA web Development using **Angular**, **Type Script**.
- Used Angular to achieve component-based application architecture using HTML and Type Script.
- Involved in **Agile process**, monthly **Sprints**, and **daily Scrums** to discuss the development of the application.
- Created client-side validation tool using technologies such as Angular JS and JavaScript.
- Support testing activities. Fixing assigned defects.
- Did Build and Deployment using Firebase

Technologies used: Angular, NodeJS, Angular Material UI, ReactJs, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript

Rekik H Biyadgilign

Dallas, TX 75243

945-257-9966 • <u>rekik.biyadgilign@gmail.com</u> • <u>Rekik Biyadgilign | LinkedIn</u> • <u>rekik</u> Work Authorization: US-Citizen

Inogen, Dallas, TX (Feb 2019- Mar 2020)

Position: UI Developer / React JS Developer

- Experience in Web Technologies using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, JQuery, AJAX, IDE, Nodejs & Tool Eclipse, and Notepad++.
- Developed Single Page Responsive Web UI using Angular 2.0, HTML5, Bootstrap, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery.
- Participated in Technical Requirements Analysis, understand business requirements and draft system requirements
- Developed Login/Registration/Edit of user profile integration with community sites using HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery, AJAX, JSON, and JavaScript.

Technologies used: Java, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Angular, Excel, SQL, XML, Eclipse.

Focus Labs, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia (Jun 2016- Oct2017)

Position: Junior Software Developer

Projects: CRM integration **Responsibilities:**

- Integrate various components of the CRM with other services
- Participate in execution and documentation of the application
- Working closely with client teams to ensure the CRM works effectively for all aspects of the company.
- Understood client business objectives and used them to produce designs that fit with their strategy.
- Review design documents with stake holders and collect approvals.
- Used Microsoft Visual Studio and Visual Studio online as an IDE

Technologies used: Java, CSS, UML, JavaScript, Angular, Excel, MySQL, XML, HTML5

EDUCATION

Master's in software development

Maharishi International University, Fairfield, Iowa • 2023

Key Courses:

Object-Oriented Programming • Algorithms • Data Structures • Modern Web Programming Server-Side Programming • Web and mobile Applications • Software Engineering

Diploma in Information Technology System Administration

MyComputerCareer - Dallas TX, USA • 2019

Bachler of Art (BA) in PSIR

Addis Ababa University - Addis Ababa, Ethiopia • 2017

CERTIFICATION

- AWS
- CompTIA
- Linux Essentials
- Microsoft Fundamentals